Edward-sama!
Is something the matter?!
It's nothing!
I told them not to disturb us...
I guess they don't trust you.
You'd feel a lot better after revealing who you really are, wouldn't you?
Fletcher!
Run! Hurry!
Brother...
If they catch you,
we won't get off easily, either!
In time, I'll clear everything up!
Al, let's go!
I'm sorry,
Brother...
Man cannot obtain anything
without first sacrificing something.
In order to obtain anything,
something of equal value is required.
That is alchemy's
Law of Equivalent Exchange.
At the time, we believed that
to be the true way of the world.
You promised not to use alchemy, right?
Dad didn't like it, you know.
Th-This is terrible!
Mugear-sama...
You two are all right!
And the stone?
Is the stone all right?
Not to worry, it's right here.
You've done well
to make it so large.
However, we don't
have any more time.
Please start using
that other method.
We don't need to use that method for the stone to—
Are you saying you won't follow my orders?
N-No...
There was once another man who told me the same thing.
In the end, he ran away,
like a beaten dog.
What's that?
With this, even without being an alchemist, I can do this!
Mugear-sama!
Magnificent!
The real Elric brothers are said to
have blond hair and golden eyes,
sons of Nash Tringham!
Things have sure been bustling over at the mansion, huh?
Oh, really?
You went there again, huh?
There's no helping you.
Huh? Is Elisa still here?
Mm-hmm.
The grapevine is withering,
so she wanted to stay here, and she won't listen to me.
But her cough is terrible.
I just put her down.
Red water?!
They're condensing it,
trying to turn it into a stone.
Then again, compared to the Philosopher's Stone,
the red-water piece is
just a pale imitation.
What do you suppose he meant by "his father's dream"?
Probably just some goofy excuse.
Could it be that those two are...
Nash's sons?
Nash?
You mean Nash Tringham,
the discoverer of the red water?
He was from this town.
He went to Central to
research the red water.
But then, one day,
he came back to this town.
Nash? Well, if it isn't Nash!
You've returned, huh?
How are you?
This town is completely
on the decline.
I think we should stop relying on gold for our way of life.
How's your research
on the red water?
Is it coming along?
I gave up.
I'll never research it again.
I'm not going back to Central, either.
What?
What about your family?
I'm a failure,
both as a husband and a father.
Nash...
He'd abandoned everything he had.
He wouldn't tell me anything about what happened in Central.
But then the big landowner in
this town—Mugear—came calling.
He approached Nash about
his research on the red water.
No matter how many times you come see me, my answer is the same!
You're saying you'd turn your back on this town?!
Right now, the only thing that can produce gold is your red water!
As long as we have gold,
the town will come back to life!
Nash-san, you're the only one
who can save this town! Please!
In the end, he secluded himself inside Mugear's mine, and began to research.
The town once again flourished because of the gold.
The furnaces were aflame, goods filled the streets,
and life returned to the people.
However, at the same time, an illness of unknown origin began to spread.
Without anyone knowing
how to treat it,
many, many babies
died soon after birth.
And Elisa was born around then?
Shortly, an alchemist doctor named Marcoh wandered into town.
The cause of this is a toxic material called
red water, which has seeped into the ground.
It glowed?!
Yes.
That light... Could it have been...
In any case, we can be sure that
thanks to his treatment, Elisa survived.
I hounded Nash.
Answer me, Nash!
If this keeps up, this will become a town of death!
What the hell have you done?!
I was in the wrong.
Again... Once again...
I'm going to end it all.
End it...
Nash...
After that, no one
ever saw him again.
Gradually, they couldn't get any more gold,
and the town once again declined.
If those two are Nash's sons,
they must have come after their father.
Brother...
What?
They had no choice.
The only thing those two have is their father.
They're just using their pop as
justification for what they're doing.
Maybe so...
But aren't we doing
something similar?
I know how those two feel.
For crying out loud!
All you had to do was shut up
and use that other method...
Brother? What method does he mean?
It's simple, really.
Have newly pregnant women drink the red water.
Soon, the water will pass through the placenta and condense...
You don't mean...
Stop!
At the right time, you get it from them and transmute it into a stone.
It's a simple, reliable method.
My, my, you've got the same sissy streak as your father.
Wait!
I just want you to
tell me one thing!
Did Dad use that method?
Hmph, at the last moment, he weaseled out.
If only he had done it,
his life would've been spared.
Why, you...
You said
Dad died from illness!
Wait!
Hey, wait!
I've taken care of everything.
Now we just have to use the real Elric brothers and put everything into action.
I doubt it will go that smoothly.
They can be very difficult to deal with.
One or two kids won't be any
trouble at all!
Now, please wait.
Please wait for
just a while longer.
Very well. Go on.
The time for this place is nigh.
I'm so sorry about
those two impostors.
I, too, was completely
taken in by them.
I feel terrible about
adding to our impertinence,
but seeing as how the two of you are among the finest alchemists of our age,
there is a matter that I would like to request your assistance with.
Research on the red water?
Oh! You know about it?
That will save me time explaining.
The truth is, I happened to overhear
that you are greatly interested in the Philosopher's Stone.
What do you think?
It was made by condensing the red water.
You might call it a trial product for a Philosopher's Stone.
What am I supposed
to do with it now?
I want to save Xenotime.
If I can regenerate the gold vein,
no one will have to give up on this town!
I get it.
So, where are the impostors?
They're being held in
an underground cell.
Wh-What are you doing?!
I'm not interested in
any unfinished goods.
Executing the impostors comes first.
I'm not the type of person who forgives liars.
Oh!
Then you're accepting my request?
With us working on it,
this will be child's play.
Never mind that, I haven't
executed anyone in a while!
I'm just itching for the chance!
Gonna come watch?
No, I, uh...
I'll pass on that.
Brother...
Hey.
Alphonse-san!
I heard that Nash Tringham was your pop.
What were you trying to do by carrying on his research?
That...
is Dad's water.
It was my duty to
continue his research.
You are such a naïve bastard.
Do you know what the people in town are going through because of that toxic water?
Your pop knew.
That's why he tried to
give up his research.
You can't obtain happiness by relying on the likes of red water or a Philosopher's Stone!
Move forward!
Don't act so shamefully!
Not now that you've
taken on my name.
Al! Let's go!
Who cares?
As long as the research is successful, those guys will be—
Those guys?
Who are you talking about?
Something's been bothering me.
Wherever did the red-water
researcher Nash Tringham go?
Nash? Ah, his research wasn't going so well, so I fired him.
Oh?
You don't seem like someone
so good-natured as to let somebody
who knew everything
get away from you.
What are you trying to say?
I'm saying that I don't help murderers out, Mugear!
Why, you!
In that case, you're not
getting out of here alive!
I can get any number of
other alchemists instead!
A stone?!
There wasn't just that one?!
It may not be as complete as that other one...
Die!
Are you done yet?
What?!
There's plenty more
where that came from!
You're kidding!
It's useless! Useless!
Equivalent exchange, my ass! Dammit!
I'm not done yet!
What is this?!
Now, Al!
Ed!
Looks like you needed my help after all.
What?!
We've given up
chasing after our dad.
We're going to go
find our own way.
Brother!
A secret passage?!
That bastard, he got away!
Russell, how much farther?
We're almost there!
There's a spring where the red water comes out!
That miserable Mugear! He blocked our way!
I'm gonna drag him out of there!
What?!
I'll never surrender the spring!
As long as I have this water, I can continue researching!
I'm not afraid of
any State Alchemist!
Ed!
Brother!
Now you've said it, Mugear!
Don't you mock the State Alchemists!
Die!
Do you see now?
I'm on an entirely
different level than you!
What's that?
Ed! That's enough!
Let's get out of here!
Brother!
I won't give up this spring!
It's the water!
The red water is overflowing!
That should hold it for now.
Are the other places all right?
The bedrock will be unstable after that shock.
Let's go!
Now, if we can just
stop it from coming out...
The trees...
They're absorbing the red water!
Brother, these kinds of trees
were in the laboratory as well!
You had them absorb the red water to detoxify it?
Brother!
Those guys did it.
Thanks.
Sorry about this.
Here. These are from Belsio-san.
Thanks!
Big Brother, take care!
Come see us again!
Mm-hmm, we'll come again for sure!
You sure you can get by in this town?
Really? Promise?
We'll accept whatever's coming to us.
Okay, let's do a parting handshake!
Working with Belsio-san, my powers will be useful.
Ed, are you still going to search for the Philosopher's Stone?
Wow, you're so big!
Yeah.
Look, how about I tell you
how to condense a red stone?
What?
Not by way of apology,
it's just that I think
you should know.
We don't need that stuff.
We'll find it on our own.
Count on it.
Ed-san! Please come again!
We're sure to make this town better!
When you do, Big Brother,
be taller, okay?
What?! Why, you!
That wasn't very nice!
Good-bye!
Bye-bye!
A letter, huh?
A letter?
Yeah. What could it be?
What?
I-It's nothing!
Show me! Show me!
Show me!
Show me, already!
Come on, Brother!
"Ed,
thanks for all your help."
"Being a year younger than you,
I'm sorry I was such a smart-aleck."
"I'm trying to be a better
older brother to Fletcher,
and I'll try hard to follow your example, Ed."
"Well, have a nice trip."
"Russell."
Damn, how can he be younger than me,
and still be taller?
What a joke!
Those two are going
to be all right, huh?
Yeah.
They had a nice,
resolute look on their faces.
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 13: "Flame VS Fullmetal"
Colonel Roy Mustang, State Alchemist.
Title: "Flame."
He's probably stronger than Brother.
Oh, no he's not!